

# **GREGORY GEORGE**

## Senior Data Analyst

- Gurgaon, Haryana
- **4** 91-7838206319
- ☑ greg.george2306@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/gregory-george-6353621a1

### Skills

- **Querying for Analysis**
- ETL using queries
- Optimization of queries.

#### Python

- ML and Data Models
- Scripting for ETL (PySpark)
- Beginner level competency with backend

#### Tableau

- Using Initial SQL
- Reports

#### Looker Studio

#### **AWS Quicksight**

- Data Sources
- Dashboarding

#### Mixpanel

- JQL

#### **Airflow**

## DataBases

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Amazon Redshift
- Google Big Query

- DynamoDB

## Objective

Detail oriented and fast paced data analyst, with 3+ years of experience in startups. Eager to bridge gaps between stake holders and enable data backed decision making. I enjoy creative data visualisation and problem solving. Working in a collaborative team across multiple verticals with strong interpersonal skills.

## Work Experience

#### Senior Data Analyst 2021-10 -

### Present

#### Colearn

- Lead the analytics team and part the data science team.
- Created a framework for user personalisation and video recommendations.
- Set up dashboards to track important metrics and insights(across product, operations and finance) using looker studio.
- Retention and User Stickiness analysis to drive up sales and enable the sales team to reach out to high intent users.
- Created Investor & CXO reports and dashboards.
- Part of team that created data-lake using AWS Glue.
- Done experimentation on product features and measures impact on users.

#### Senior Analyst - Business Intelligence 2020-02 -

#### 2021-10

### **IND Money**

- Part of the 2 member team to set up the entire reporting process and built multiple
- Created an ETL process to create flat tables to enable self service of data for multiple
- Setup CXO dashboard using tableau to track data at one place across the whole organization with multi filters and interactive filters.
- Create complex time series data-sources in tableau using cross database join feature
- Used Inital SQL feature of tableau to help create tables just for tableau analysis.
- Created a propensity model to help identify users for subscription.
- Created multiple pipelines to get data from different sources and combine them finally in a redshift warehouse using airflow and python.
- Setup dashboards and data sources for multiple pods using tableau, metabase and redash.
- Generated insights into each product and helped identify key issue areas to drive up business For eg. found a major drop off area in the onboarding process with maximum user drop off.

### 2018-07 -

2019-12

# PhD. Scholar

## Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi

- Was pursuing a PhD. in atmospheric sciences, working on climate data analysis using python and atmospheric models.
- Did extensive research in collecting data from multiple sources and aggregating them to use for analysis.
- Did regression and correlation analysis with certain climate indices v/s pressure and wind vectors to predict extreme events.

#### 2016-05 -Intern

## 2016-07

## The Energy Research Institute, Delhi

- Part of project with the World Health Organization(WHO) to measure indoor air quality in offices.
- Did collection, aggregation and analysis of raw data to drive insights.
- Created the final report for presentation to WHO.

### Education

2015 - 2017

Master of Science: Environmental Sciences and Technology

Central University of Punjab

Pesticide residue analysis in tomatoes using SPSS and linear regression.

Bachelor of Science: Chemistry (Hons) 2011 - 2014

St. Stephen's College, Delhi University